But you have no expenses either.
No.
You get free accommodation and food.
Yes and all trips home on leave paid.
So I really had no expenses, it was a little candy type you buy on the weekends.
But otherwise it really is, most people save that money.
And then you get a lump sum.
What you have earned you get again when you have finished the education as well.
So if you do for nine months you have received 40 thousand -
- And so you get it again, so 80,000 then.
Tax -free.
Yeah.
And I did 15 months as KB, as it is called, company fäls -
- And 15 months times the four thousand you get a month will be a little more maybe.
It was a nice cling at the checkout when I got there, the day we finished.
Yes but a little this macho culture.
Everyone should be big, strong, tough ... endure a lot
But I noticed that pretty quickly -
- That no one was prepared for what was waiting in the beginning.
And then I ended up on a fairly technically oriented pluton then.
There was everyone like me.
A little nature interested, or had this interest in plugging and so on.
Yes and a little similar, though, it is for me, because it was not very theory in my position -
- Out it was more out and pig in the forest type.
So I thought everyone would be this huge, strong man -
- But I fit in very well there and I'm not that stereotype.
So that I think it is very much wider than you think.
Then it is also an education, and that was perhaps not what I had mainly in my head -
For me a little the same, the worst memories are also the best in some way because they are the ones you learn most from I think.
Mine was probably ... we had a soldier's test so we had done this and tested without food and such ...
... how do you manage for a few days.
And it would have been shit.
But after that we had a job training ...
... and then I would have the shotgun for the first time,
Also, we would have a march to learn to go with it and pall the packing -
- And then I wore the charging bag, ie where you have all the bullets to shoot -
- And it gets pretty heavy because there is a lot to shoot.
So I thought it was ... It's my worst memory, but there I really learned ...
... it was probably the first time during the entire undergraduate education, then I had been in for a while -
- As I really felt that shit what I pallets more than I think.
Nah.
-No.
I thought it was very nice that there is no difference between women and men.
Then you may notice as a woman that like this, you are a minority -
- But I would say that the commanders, ie the teachers I had during my education - -
- They were very good that if we were out in the field we also got five minutes to pee -
- That every time you like this, I request more time, so I can't pee in five minutes -
- You may have had menstruation or so, then they were very very understanding.
And I only had male commanders, so for me it was a bit of a shock in the beginning that they were so understanding.
I thought it would be much harder than it was.
And what are fields?
Should we start there?
We can start with fields.
I have a little control over.
Yes, you have to do that.
It is always possible to have a map in your pocket.
So I really didn't see myself as a typical military and still don't do it -
—The far from the stereotypical image I had before I did my military duty -
- That it would be very macho and you would be very big, strong and you would have an interest in being out in the woods -
- And maybe different weapons systems that some find interesting.
I was like this, I liked to hang out with friends, make up, I liked clothes ...
... So, it was really as far away as I could imagine that you could be from the Armed Forces and the military.
But I enjoy it very well and have found something that I really like.
So even though I really didn't see myself as the stereotypical military, I'm a military now.
Yes but exactly.
And I recognize myself a lot in it because I saw myself pretty much like ...
... I am not strong enough and not enough on and forward, and I like to joke about it a little and so -
- And be a little lattjo, and it doesn't fit in because there it should be strict and "up oppos".
I'm a little more in the geeky direction maybe.
You are actually needed there, even if you think you are a reading head that may not have sports as a favorite subject.
And it has boosted my self -esteem so much because I thought a little about myself before the military service.
Yes but that was for me too.
You get a bigger perspective, I would say, on things.
Although I might like to make up, or still do -
- So I can live in the forest without doing it, so I do not die from it.
So that you learn a lot about yourself and you learn to appreciate things a lot.
I think we can appreciate a hot shower, more than many who have not done military service can, for example.
Or a bed.
A bed!